Guide to the Jane L. Berdes Papers, 1525-1993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jane L. Berdes papers 1525-1993
Berdes, Jane L., 1931-1993
79.5 linear feet Extent: 46,000 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00107
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection contains many photocopies and microfilm copies of items which belong to other libraries and archives. Photocopies of materials gathered from other repositories by Jane Berdes may require permission of the owner institution to further reproduce or publish. Also, in the collection there are unmarked photocopies of materials from other repositories that Berdes made from microfilm (in the Music Series, Microfilm Subseries). Users making further copies for their own research do so at their own discretion. Before publication of any such materials, it is the researcher's responsibility to identify the original source and obtain permission.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The papers (1525-1993) of Dr. Jane L. Berdes (1931-1993) were donated to the Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1993 by her husband, George Berdes.
Biographical Note
1931, Sept. 13 Born
1953 Received B.A. in Journalism from Marquette University
1972 Received grant from the National Music Critics Association
1979 Received M.M. in Musicology from University of Maryland
1982 Received an award from the National Endowment for the Humanities
1983 Enrolled in Wolfson College, Oxford University
1984 Received grants from the American Association of University Women and Wolfson College, Oxford University
1989 Received PhD in Musicology from Oxford University
1989-1993 Honorary Fellow in the University of Wisconsin-Madison Women's Studies Program; Women's Studies Research Center
1990 Instructor, Department of Music, Madison Area Technical College
1991 Instructor, Outreach Program, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Published modern edition of Violin Concertos by Maddalena Laura Sirmen (1745-1818), Recent Researches in Music of the Classical Era, Vol. 38
1993 Published Women Musicians of Venice: Musical Foundations, 1525-1855 (Oxford University Press)
1993, Aug. 31 Died
Berdes was a member of the following professional organizations: American Association of University Professors; American Musicological Society; American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies; College Music Society; Royal Musical Association; British Scholars' Venetian Seminar; Early Music America; Music Critics Association; and British Society for Renaissance Studies.
Collection Overview
The Jane L. Berdes Collection (1525-1993) has as its focal points the four Venetian welfare institutions known as the Ospedali Grandi and their role as providers of musical training for girls and women. The inclusive dates for the collection begin with the dates of primary materials Berdes collected and extend through her lifetime. The collection consists primarily of Berdes's research notes and materials on the Ospedali Grandi, and photocopies or microfilms of primary sources, including musical scores in manuscript and printed editions. It also contains correspondence, photographs, recordings and printed materials. Berdes identified the maestri of the Ospedali Grandi, the music performed, and the names of over 800 women who were members of the cori, but relatively little is known about them individually with the exception of Maddalena Lombardini Sirmen. In addition, the collection features general materials pertaining to other women in music throughout history. The user is advised that some photocopies are unattributed and, where Berdes did not indicate composer or author, no attempt has been made to provide one. The archive contains very few of Berdes's personal papers.
The bulk of the collection is found in the Research Notes and Materials Series, which contains information gathered in preparation for her books on the Ospedali Grandi and Maddalena Lombardini Sirmen (MLS). The heart of this series is the Ospedali Grandi data designated as Raw Materials, which contains information culled from primary sources and arranged by subject. Most subseries provide documentation for Raw Materials, including copies of primary and secondary sources, pictures of instruments and iconography, and a bibliography. Similar materials pertaining to Sirmen are here also, as is general information about women in music.
The Music Series contains manuscripts and early printed editions of music performed at the Ospedali Grandi in the form of photocopies or microfilms (printed scores in modern edition are grouped with Printed Materials). There is particular emphasis on the compositions of Sirmen, including some recordings of her music. Works by Bertoni, Galuppi, Hasse, Jommelli, Vivaldi and others are grouped alphabetically by composer. The Correspondence Series contains both general professional correspondence and Thesis Correspondence, that is letters from other scholars, libraries, archives, museums, and churches in Italian, French and English concerning the Ospedali Grandi and Sirmen. The Miscellaneous Series includes Berdes's other publications on both musical and nonmusical subjects, music criticism, course notes from classes she taught or attended, and memorabilia from her years at Oxford University. A selection of pertinent reference books from Berdes's library is found in the Printed Material Series, as are some libretti, and musical scores by Vivaldi in modern edition.
The user is advised to consult Box #1 for an introduction to the contents of the collection. It contains a copy of Berdes's book Women Musicians in Venice: Musical Foundations, 1525-1855; two copies of her dissertation, entitled Musical Life at the Four Ospedali Grandi, 1525-1855; two binders described by the donor as the road map to the collection and a videotaped review of its contents prepared by Berdes.
Local Subject Headings
Sirmen, Maddalena Laura Lombardini, 1745-1818; Ospedale degli Incurabili (Venice, Italy); Ospedale della pieta (Venice, Italy); Ospedale di Santa Maria dei Derelitti (Venice, Italy); Ospedale di San Lazaro e dei Mendicanti (Venice, Italy); Women musicians -- Italy; Music -- Manuscripts; Women composers -- Italy; Music -- Italy -- History and criticism; Charities -- Italy -- Venice -- History; Scores
Contents of Collection
- Published Materials and Guides, (1 box)
  - Archive review videotape (Box 1)
  - Women Musicians in Venice: Musical foundations, 1525-1855 (Box 1)
  - White binders which are guides to the archive, (2 binders) (Box 1)
  - Dissertation in binder: Musical Life at the Four Ospedali Grandi, 1525-1855 (Box 1)
  - Bound copy of Musical Life at the Four Ospedali Grandi, 1525-1855 (Box 1)
  - Dissertation bibliography (Box 1)
- Research Notes and Materials, ca. 1700-1993
  Mainly photocopies and microfilms of primary documents and secondary sources, writings and notes associated with those sources, bibliography materials, and data culled from primary archival sources and organized by topic. Also includes printed documents which were originally on computer disk. Divided into sixteen subseries.
  - Repertoire: (Box 2)
    - 1687-1770 (Box 2)
    - 18th century (Box 2)
    - Liturgy, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Genres (Box 2)
    - Motets, 1760s (Box 2)
    - Derelitti/Motet, 1750s (Box 2)
    - Incurabile/Motets and Dialoghi, 18th century, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Mendicanti/Motets, 1770s (Box 2)
    - Derelitti/Solo Motets, 1770s (Box 2)
    - Incurabile/Solo Motets, 1760s (Box 2)
    - Mendicanti/Solo Motets, 1750s (Box 2)
    - Pieta/Solo Motets, 1770s (Box 2)
    - Cantatas, Serenatas, 1760s (Box 2)
    - Oratorio (Box 2)
    - Derelitti/Oratorios, 1770s (Box 2)
    - Incurabile/Oratorios, 1700 (Box 2)
    - Mendicanti, 18th century (Box 2)
    - Mendicanti/Oratorios, 1700 (Box 2)
    - Pietà/Oratorios, 1715 (Box 2)
    - Sacred Vocal Works, 18th century: Alpha by composer, A-Z, (8 folders) (Box 2)
    - Sacred Vocal Works, Anonymous, 18th century (Box 2)
    - General, (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - St. Mark's Archive at St. Apollonia, 1720-1870, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Archive and Library holdings:
    - Benedetto Marcello, 18th century, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Archive and Library holdings, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Institution:
    - Derelitti, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Incurabile (Box 4)
    - Mendicanti, (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - Pietà, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Institution: Pietà (Box 5)
  - Ospedali Grandi:
    - General history in 9 stages, (7 folders) (Box 5)
    - Contemporary correspondence (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, (9 folders) (Box 5)
    - Documents, (18 folders) (Box 6)
    - Contemporary commentary, (11 folders) (Box 7)
    - Secondary sources, (7 folders) (Box 7)
    - Secondary sources, (18 folders) (Box 8)
    - Secondary sources, (17 folders) (Box 9)
    - Folders 28-30 are CLOSED. (Box 9)
    - Secondary sources, (16 folders) (Box 10)
    - Secondary sources, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Model for other institutions, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Iconography, (13 folders) (Box 11)
  - Bibliography files, (4 boxes) (Box 12)
  - Bibliography files, (4 boxes) (Box 13)
  - Bibliography files, (4 boxes) (Box 14)
  - Bibliography files, (3 boxes) (Box 15)
  - Bibliography files, (2 boxes) (Box 16)
  - Instruments, (5 folders) (Box 17)
  - Maestri and composers, (7 folders) (Box 17)
  - Venice, (4 folders) (Box 17)
  - Venice, (9 folders) (Box 18)
  - Women Musicians in Venice:
    - Chapter II, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Chapter III, (4 folders) (Box 18)
  - Women Musicians in Venice: Chapter III (Box 19)
  - Raw materials:
    - Repertoire (Box 19)
    - Institution populations (Box 19)
    - Fact sheet (Box 19)
    - Figlie di Coro, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Musical chronology (Box 19)
    - Maestri and composers (Box 19)
    - Contemporary commentary, (4 folders) (Box 19)
    - Obligations of Coro Inserviente (Box 19)
    - Librettists (Box 19)
    - Glossary; Guide to Library Siglia (Box 19)
    - Patrons and benefactors (Box 19)
    - Liturgical State calendars (Box 19)
    - Government; Aristocracy structure (Box 19)
    - Iconography; Instruments (Box 19)
    - Plates (Box 19)
  - Post Dissertation: Research ideas, (6 folders) (Box 19)
  - Post Dissertation: Research ideas (Box 20)
  - Funding Proposals, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS):
    - Dessimination (Box 20)
    - Draft of book (Box 20)
    - Documents v.I-v.III, (10 folders) (Box 20)
    - Watermarks (Box 20)
    - Iconography (Box 20)
    - Marriage information (Box 20)
  - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS): (Box 21)
    - Bibliography (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box 21)
    - Tartini, (3 folders) (Box 21)
  - Women in Music:
    - Venice (Box 21)
    - Seeger, Ruth Crawford, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - History course, (3 folders) (Box 21)
  - Women in Music: (Box 22)
    - History course, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, (12 folders) (Box 22)
  - Bouquet-Boyer (Box 22)
  - Gastone Vio, (3 folders) (Box 23)
  - Research Notes and Materials Series (Microfilm).
    Arranged by topic in alphabetical order.
    - Libretti (3 reels) (Box 23 A)
    - Oratorio Libretti (Box 23 A)
    - Libretto (Box 23 A)
    - Libretti (Box 23 A)
    - Alessiani (Box 23 A)
    - Bianchini (Box 23 A)
    - Bona (Box 23 A)
    - Bona, (2 reels) (Box 23 B)
    - Caffi (Box 23 B)
    - Concini (Box 23 B)
    - Fort (Box 23 B)
    - Giacomo (Box 23 B)
    - Ivanovich (Box 23 B)
    - Kiesewetter (Box 23 B)
    - Maiers (Box 23 B)
    - Meyerbaer (Box 24 C)
    - Murari (Box 24 C)
    - Ortes (Box 24 C)
    - Rudolf (Box 24 C)
    - Sceriman, (2 reels) (Box 24 C)
    - Selvaggi (Box 24 C)
    - Swale (Box 24 C)
    - Tartini (Box 24 C)
    - Venetian ambassador to spain (Box 24 D)
    - Capitoli, (2 reels) (Box 24 D)
    - Cistercian (Box 24 D)
    - Disgrazie (Box 24 D)
    - Figlie (Box 24 D)
    - Guistiniani (Box 24 D)
    - Inventario (Box 24 D)
    - Maps (Box 24 D)
    - Memoire, (2 reels) (Box 24 E)
    - Ordini (Box 24 E)
    - Sovegno (Box 24 E)
    - Storia (Box 24 E)
    - Terminazione (Box 24 E)
    - Pardies (Box 24 E)
    - Parte (Box 24 E)
    - Pieta (Box 24 E)
  - Photocopies (Alphabetical) Subseries
    - Esposti, (9 reels) (Box 24 F)
    - Esposti (4 reels) (Box 25 G)
- Music Series
  - Music, ca. 1700-1850.
    Includes photocopies (arranged alphabetically by composer), microfilm and cassette recordings of music.
    - Alessani (Box 25 G)
    - Anfossi (Box 25 G)
    - Bertoni, (2 folders) (Box 25 G)
    - Bianchi (Box 25 G)
    - Carcani (Box 25 G)
    - Cimarosa (Box 25 G)
    - Cordans (Box 25 G)
    - Furlanetto, (2 folders) (Box 25 G)
    - Galuppi:
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 25 G)
      - Dixit Dominus (Box 25 G)
      - Sacrifizio di Jephte (Box 25 G)
    - Hasse: Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 25 G)
    - Hasse: (Box 26)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 26)
      - Fanciulli (Box 26)
      - Poplo ebreo nel Deserto (Box 26)
      - Serpentes in Deserto (Box 26)
      - Toillite Hostias (Box 26)
    - Haydn: Cantata d'Ariana (Box 26)
    - Jommelli:
      - Miscellaneous (Box 26)
      - Miserere (Box 26)
    - Lodovico Sirmen (LS):
      - Sei Duetti/Print (Venice: Zatta and Figli, 1789) I-Vc V219 (Box 26)
      - String Trio in G Major: Unpub. Mss: I-An Ms. Mus. 89. Attr. to Lodovico Sirmen (Box 26)
      - Sei Trii. op1/ Print (Amsterdam: Hummel, 1769) GB-Cku RW 27.233-G, item 10 (Box 26)
      - Violin Concerto in Bb Major: Mss. I-Gl M.3b.24.26 (Box 26)
      - Quartet No. 1 in Eb Major Mss.: I-Gl M.3b. 2u.23 (Box 26)
      - Quartets: Mss. I-An Ms. Mus.28. Attr. to Lodovico Sirmen (Box 26)
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS):
      - Rondo (Box 26)
      - Overture in Bb Major: I-Mc. N/L6-5, No. 18 (Box 26)
  - Photocopies (Alphabetical) Subseries (One original ms. included)
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS):
      - Quartet fragment: GB-Cpl Ms. 81, No. 21 (clarinetto) (Box 26)
      - Quartet No. 3 in Bb (= No. 4) Ms. I-Bc kk.126 Atti. to MLS (Box 26)
      - Six Quartets:
        - Six Quartets/Print (Box 26)
        - I-Nc Ms. 22.3.8 "ML-S" Eb, Bb, f, E, S.Bb (Box 26)
        - Print (Paris: Berault, 1769) gb-Lbm S.413 (Box 26)
        - Print (London: Wm. Napier, 1773) Gb-Cu Mr320 a. 75401 (Box 26)
        - Six Trios / Opus1. London: Welcker, 1771. Gb Lbm s. 471 (Box 26)
      - Six Trios: Op. 1, Mss. (Box 26)
      - String Trio:
        - Mss. Trio in F attributed to Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (=No. 6 of L. S. Op. 1) I-Ds Musiche 2797 (Box 26)
        - Trois in Bb unpublished. Private collection, Modena, Original Ms. and photocopies (Box 26)
        - Mss. Trios in D (No. 3) and G (No. 5). I-Bc kk. 126 (Box 26)
        - Opus 1: Ms. D-DDR-Bds; Ms-5186-5191 (Box 26)
      - Duets: Miscellaneous (Box 26)
      - Six Duets: Prints:
        - Op. 5: Print: Paris, Venier 1775. F-pbn, k 6077 (Box 26)
        - London: Napier, 1773:
          - E-Mn. M.1684-1685/5 (Box 26)
          - Gb=Lbm g.421.r. /12. [g. 413] (Box 26)
        - B. Hummel, 1773 (Box 26)
      - Duet No. 2 in D Major: Mss. I-Os, Mss. Musiche B 2796 (Box 26)
      - Violin Duet in C, No. 6: Mss. I-Mc. A.27.18.4 (Box 26)
      - Violin Duet in E, No. 4: Mss. I-Gl. Attributed to Lodovico Sirmen (Box 26)
      - Six Duets: I-Gl. N.1.6.6. (Sc. 17) (Box 26)
      - Trois concerts Opus 2: Print: (Amsterdam, Hummel, 1772) E-Mn M709-716/9 (Box 26)
      - Six Concerts: Print, Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 26)
      - Concerto (Box 27)
      - Six Violin Concertos: Print (Box 27)
      - Six Trios Opus1/s Musik Museet (Box 27)
      - Six Violin Concertos: Print (London: Wlm. Napier, 1773) E-Mn M6888-899/1 (Box 27)
      - Concertos opp. 2, 3, 4/Print (Paris: Borrelly, 1775-1777) S-Skma (Box 27)
      - Two Trios/Print: ed. by Lauro Malusi, 1983 (Box 27)
      - Adagio aus einem Violinkonzert: Print (Box 27)
      - Violin Concerto in E, No. 2: Mss I-NC Ms 9651 (No. X. 1983) (Box 27)
      - Six Concertos, Opus 2/Mss (Amsterdam: 1772) S-L sam1. Kraus (Box 27)
      - Concerto in G Major for flute w/violin obbl./Mss I-Pca N.1744.D.V. (Box 27)
      - A Concerto/Print (London: Napier, 1772). US-WC M1012.S.62.Op.3.p (Box 27)
      - Six Concertos in 9 parts /Print (London: Napier, 1773) US WC M1012.S62.Op.3 (Box 27)
      - Trois Concerts/Print (Box 27)
      - Trois Concerts/Prints, NL-DHgm 3946.75, B. Muz. (Box 27)
      - Trois Concerts Opus 2/Print (Amsterdam: 1772, GB Cku 23.185) (Box 27)
      - Three Concertos/Prints (Box 27)
      - Concerto a Violino Solo con suoi Ripieni/Mss (Box 27)
      - Violin Concerto in C, No. 10 (=6) Mss Cs-B 89-D, A8 (Box 27)
      - Concerto No. 1 in Bb Major/Mss I-Tra N. 749/X.13.N.17 (Box 27)
      - Violin Concerto in Bb, No. 1/Mss I-Gl M.3b.24.25 (Box 27)
      - Violin Concerto in B flat No. 1 Mss I-Vnm Cod.It.Iv.1524 (11472) (Box 27)
      - Violin Concerto in Bb No. 1 (reads No. 4) Mss I-Bc kk.126 (Box 27)
      - Violin Concerto in A, No. 3 I-Os. Mss Musiche B.2795 (Box 27)
      - Trois Concerts, Giordani Transcription (Napier) D-DDR-WRz Mss (Box 27)
      - Six Concertos for the Harpsichord transcribed by Giordani: Print (Box 27)
      - Giordani Transcriptions (London: Napier, 1773) GB Lbm R.M. 17.c.4 (Box 27)
      - Giordani Concerto Transcriptions US-WC M1011 S64.Op. 3. G5 US-NY pl 15862DA (Box 27)
      - Six Trios. Opus 1/s-Musik Museet (Box 27)
      - Six Trios. Opus 1/Print (Box 27)
      - Six Trios. Op. 1/Print (Paris: Sieber, 1771) F-Pc K6076 (Box 27)
      - Six Trios, Opus1/Prints (Box 27)
      - Violin Sonata in A Major (Box 27)
      - Six Sonates Op. 4/Print (Amsterdam: B Hummel, 1773) NH-DHgm (Box 27)
      - Six Sonates a Deux Violons Moravian Music Foundation (Box 27)
      - Unpublished Concertos (Box 27)
      - Violin Concertos/Berdes, editor, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Violin Concertos: Berdes, editor (Box 28)
      - Marsand (Box 28)
      - Martini (Box 28)
      - Monteverdi (Box 28)
      - Mozart (Box 28)
      - Pampani (Box 28)
      - Pollarolo (Box 28)
      - Porpora (Box 28)
      - Sacchini (Box 28)
      - Salari (Box 28)
      - Scarlatti, A. (Box 28)
      - Tartini (Box 28)
      - Valentini (Box 28)
      - Vivaldi (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 28)
  - Microfilm Subseries, ca. 1700-1850.
    Microfilm filed by last name of composer whose work appears first on reel. Reels may contain works by multiple composers.
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (9 boxes) (Box 28 A)
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (2 reels) (Box 28 B)
    - Sirmen (Box 28 B)
    - Bassani (Box 28 B)
    - Bertoni (Box 28 B)
    - Bernasconi (Box 28 B)
    - Calegari (Box 28 B)
    - Como (Box 28 B)
    - Cimarosa (Box 29 C)
    - Fantoni (Box 29 C)
    - Furlanetto (5 reels) (Box 29 C)
    - Galuppi (2 reels) (Box 29 C)
    - Galuppi (Box 29 D)
    - Gasparini (Box 29 D)
    - Giordano (2 reels) (Box 29 D)
    - Hasse (3 reels) (Box 29 D)
    - Jommelli (2 reels) (Box 29 D)
    - Jommelli (Box 29 E)
    - Latilla (3 reels) (Box 29 E)
    - Marcello (Box 29 E)
    - Martinelli (Box 29 E)
    - Martini (Box 29 E)
    - Mozart (Box 29 E)
    - Pallavicino (Box 29 E)
    - Pampani (Box 29 F)
    - Pescetti (Box 29 F)
    - Porpora (Box 29 F)
    - Pollarola (2 reels) (Box 29 F)
    - Raffaele (Box 29 F)
    - Rovetta (Box 29 F)
    - Sarti (2) (Box 29 F)
    - Tartini (Box 30G)
    - Vinacessi (Box 30G)
    - Vivaldi (Box 30G)
    - Cantatas (Box 30G)
    - Canzonettas (Box 30G)
    - Six Quartets (Box 30G)
    - Organ Sonatas (Box 30G)
    - Popular Songs (Box 30G)
    - Violin Concerto (Box 30G)
  - Cassette Recordings Subseries
    - 1 box cassettes (Box 30G)
- Correspondence, ca. 1972-1993.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - General, 1972-1994, (7 folders) (Box 30G)
  - Thesis, 1974-1979 (Box 30G)
  - Thesis, 1980 -1991, (4 folders) (Box 31)
  - Women's Studies Research Center, 1993 (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-1992 (Box 31)
- Miscellaneous, 1950-1993.
  Arranged by topic.
  - Berdes: (Box 31)
    - Publications:, (9 folders) (Box 31)
    - Publications: Not scholarly, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - At Oxford, (3 folders) (Box 32)
  - Berg (Box 32)
  - Chopin (Box 32)
  - Dissertation plates (Box 32)
  - 18th century keyboard concerto course (Box 32)
  - Funding proposals, (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - Hayden:
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
    - String Quartets (Box 32)
  - Liturgical (Box 33)
  - Lombardini-Sirmen, Maddalena (Box 33)
  - Medieval Music history course, (5 folders) (Box 33)
  - Meyer-Baer, Kathi (Box 33)
  - Monographs, (5 folders) (Box 33)
  - Mozart bicentennial (Box 33)
  - Music criticism, (4 folders) (Box 33)
  - Music criticism, (5 folders) (Box 34)
  - Music history, (8 folders) (Box 34)
  - Music history, (13 folders) (Box 35)
  - Music history, (12 folders) (Box 36)
  - 19th Century Music course, (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - 20th Century Music course, (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - 20th Century Music course, (6 folders) (Box 37)
  - Venetian Art (Box 37)
  - Women's Studies, (7 folders) (Box 37)
- Printed Material Series
  Includes books, scores and libretti in modern editions.
  - Books Subseries
    - Ammiriamo, Venezia (Box 38)
    - Arte Veneta (Box 38)
    - L' Archivio I.R.E. (Box 38)
    - Arte e Musica all' Ospedaletto (Box 38)
    - The Prado (Box 38)
    - Basilica (Box 38)
    - Catalogo Della Pinacoteca (Box 38)
    - A Catalogue of 18th Century Symphonies (Box 38)
    - Catalog of Pre-1900 Vocal Manuscripts in the Music library, University of California at Berkeley (Box 38)
    - The Civilization of the Renaissance in Italy (Box 38)
    - The Companion Guide to Venice (Box 38)
    - Il Conservatorio Di Musica Benedetto Marcello Di Venezia (Box 38)
    - Culture Et Pouvoir Dans: Les Etats de Savpoe Die VII Siecle a la Revolution (Box 38)
    - Daily Life in Venice (at the time of Casanova) (Box 38)
    - Dizionario del Dialetto Veniziano (Box 38)
    - Difesa della sanità a Venezia (Box 38)
    - The Drawings of Andrea Palladio (Box 38)
    - Dizionario of Elbbreviature latine ed italiane (Box 38)
    - An Eighteenth-Century Musical Chronicle (Box 39)
    - The Eighteenth-Century Woman (Box 39)
    - Ars Musica Musica Scientia (Box 39)
    - Five Centuries of Music in Venice (Box 39)
    - Francesco Gasparini (1661-1727) (Box 39)
    - Il Fondo Musicale Dell'I.R.E. Instituzioni Di Ricoveroe Di Educazione Di Venezia (Box 39)
    - The Genius of Venice, 1500-1600 (Box 39)
    - A History of Venice (Box 39)
    - Music and the Culture in Italy from the Middle Ages to the Baroque (Box 39)
    - Music in the Middle Ages (Box 39)
    - Music in the Renaissance (Box 39)
    - Ospedaletteo La Sala Della Musica (Box 39)
    - The Oratorio in Venice (Box 39)
    - nuova rivista musicale italiana (Box 39)
    - Pallade Veneta (Box 40)
    - Nel Regno Dei Poveri (Box 40)
    - San Girolamo Miani E Venizia (Box 40)
    - La Sculoa Musicale Di Napoli (4 vols.) (Box 40)
    - Storia Della Cultura Veneta (Box 40)
    - Thematic Catalog of a Manuscript Collection of Eighteenth-Century (Box 40)
    - Italian Instrumental Music (Box 40)
    - Venice (A Docmentary History, 1450-1630) (Box 40)
    - Venice (a travellers' companion) (Box 40)
    - Venice and Its Lagoon (Box 40)
    - Venezia (Box 40)
    - Venice (The Biography of a City) (Box 40)
    - Virtuose in Italy, 1600-1640 (Box 40)
  - Libretto Subseries (Box 41)